

#### CONTACT

- Porto, Portugal
- □ +351 91 615 15 65
- ✓ ricarraf@gmail.com
- /ricardojaferreira
- /RicardoAraujoFerreira

## PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES



#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

Spring • PlayFramework • Laravel • ReactJS • Apache • Nginx • Git • MySql / MariaDB • PostgreSQL • MongoDB • Docker • ElasticSearch • Couchbase • RabbitMQ • Hazelcast • Jenkins • Cucumber

#### **LANGUAGES**



#### OPERATING SYSTEMS



**ACTIVITIES** 



See the extended version at https://git.io/fh5zG.

# Ricardo Jorge de Araújo Ferreira

Electrical and Computer Science Engineer (M.Sc.) Student of Master in Informatics and Computing Engineering

# **SUMMARY**

I am currently working has a full stack developer in an Agile (scrum) environment with modern technologies, previleging good quality code and architectures. To learn more about software development I have started the Master Degree in Informatics and Computing Engineering at Faculdade de Engenharia, I am currently at the 4rd year out of a 5 year program.

# **EXPERIENCE**

Web Engineer - Fullstack Developer

2018/02 - now

Jumia - Porto Tech Center

Porto, Portugal

- Development of web applications using JAVA frameworks, like Spring boot and Play;
- Working in a team with the DevOps culture and interest in state of the art thechnology.

Software Engineer - Fullstack Developer GravityDemand, Lda - E-Commerce

2014/05 - 2018/02 Penafiel, Portugal

- Development of software for ecommerce and marketing solutions;
- Development and integration with external services (REST and other API's).

R&D - Engineer

2012/01 - 2014/05

Porto, Portugal

INESC - Institute for System and Computer Engineering

- Research and testing in the power energy field (software and hardware);
- Validate emerging concepts in Smart-Grids with prototypes and models.
- Automation Engineer

2008/08 - 2012/01

Efacec, Sistemas de Engenharia

Maia, Portugal

- Development of control and automation systems;
- Management of large information systems based on UNIX platforms.

## **EDUCATION**

- M.Sc. in Informatics and Computation Engineering Porto, Portugal Faculdade de Eng. da Universidade do Porto
  - Currently at the 4rd Year, 2 more to finish the graduation.

M.Sc. in Electrical and Computers Engineering Faculdade de Eng. da Universidade do Porto

**Present** 

Porto, Portugal

Present

Specialization: Automation and Control Systems

▶ Thesis: Solar Car - Control and development. (17 out of 20)